<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Richa Sharma</title>
    <link>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Richa Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Sentiment Analysis - COVID-19 Tweets</title>
      <link>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this project, I have created a classification system for COVID-19 tweets: positive, negative, neutral.
I have used Naive Bayes and Logistic Regression classification and bag-of-words features.
Data Used Data has been downloaded from the Kaggle website.
Preprocessing Preprocessing is the first step, before training the data. Following steps has been used to clean the tweets:
 removed urls removed twitter usernames that begins with @ removed hashtags removed digits converted commas etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project II: Regression models - Ocean water Temperature Vs Salinity</title>
      <link>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this project, I have created different regression models to predict the Ocean Temperature based on the Ocean Salinity.
Following models were applied to the dataset:
 Simple Linear Regression Polynomial Linear Regression Support Vector Regression Decision Tree Regression Random Forest Regression  Data Used Data has been downloaded from the Kaggle website.
Data Accuracy Support Vector Regression was the best model to predict the Ocean Temperature based on the Ocean Salinity with an accuracy of 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project III: Time-Series Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this project, I have analysed time-series data of air passengers and using machine learning models, I have predicted how the future trend will change for the number of passengers.
I have used ARINA and SARINA model for forecasting.
Data Used Data has been downloaded from the Kaggle website.
Preprocessing  I looked for the different components of the time-series data such as seasonality and trend by using decomposition. Checked for stationarity of the time-series using ADF test and rolling statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://richashama.github.io/Data-Science-portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rsharma93/    Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
